The following is a production of
DallasCowboys.com and the Dallas Cowboys
football club. How about theowboy?
>> This is Mick Shots.
>> Streaming live on dallascowboys.com
and the official Dallas Cowboys app
>> presented by Miller Light, the only beer
of the Cowboys. It's Miller time. And
now your hosts, Mickey Spagnola, Everson
Walls, Hecma Harrison, and Bill Jones.
>> It's Miller time and it's Mickey time
here on Mick Shot.
>> This early.
>> Very nice.
>> Miller time. This early. Wow.
>> Well, it's brought to you by
>> crack one open.
>> Miller, the only beer of the Dallas
Cowboys. This is Mick Shots, Bill Jones,
Everson Walls, Hecma Harrison, and
Mickey Spagnola. And with your voice,
man.
>> I just noticed first
>> sound sexy or something. That ain't he
sounds
>> very white here.
>> He hadn't talked to anybody today yet.
>> I had something coming on last night.
>> White Barry White.
>> I got I got I'll tell you right off the
top. I wasn't sure if I was going to
make it when I went to bed last night,
but through a amazing recovery
overnight. There you go, man. So, here I
am. It's allergies, I guess. Sounds like
you should say it like a tradition like
a
>> Let's get it on.
>> I had no idea my voice sounded like that
as I talked.
>> Oh man,
>> it's going to be good.
>> So, everyone else talks. Let's make fun
of your voices.
>> We normal. Yeah, we're here. We're us.
>> Lead us, Bill.
>> We're all ears.
>> I was afraid I wasn't going to get here
in time.
Good thing we don't do this show at
9:00.
>> Had some traffic issues, huh?
>> Oh, Lord. I felt like I was in a road
race.
>> Yeah. Kind of get into it with a guy
today.
>> Oh, you did. Really? Road rage,
>> you know. Hey, hey, hey, watch out,
buddy. You kind of
>> crashing cars.
>> Trying to figure out what kind of day
was it? Thursday. Why is everybody like
going to work?
>> What time do you normally go to work?
>> Huh?
Depends if I work out in the morning or
not.
>> Okay. But it's after rush hour.
>> Oh yeah. Not at 9:00.
>> Why? Why would you if you didn't have
to?
>> Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> And this reinforced it.
>> But Heck seemed like an early morning
guy.
>> I am. I got here early, had breakfast,
had I mean, what is wrong with you guys?
>> Amazing.
>> That guy.
>> He's an easy drive in this morning, man.
So pleasant.
>> At 6:30. Everybody
>> had a chance to watch the rounds of the
Masters.
>> Sun come up.
>> Yes. I mean, guys,
>> it's a great place to be first thing in
the morning.
>> Hey, you wake up at 4:00 now.
>> 4:00.
>> Yeah.
>> What time you go to bed?
>> I mean, you go to bed.
>> I go to bed at 8:30, 9:00. I'm done.
>> Wow.
>> I'm out.
>> You're a man, bro. That's That's You're
a man, bro.
>> You're like my dad, man. I'm like, why
do people do this stuff? When my dad
used to get up so early in the morning,
like
>> that's that's my wife. She's
>> Hey, man.
>> in bed by 9:00, up by 4.
>> One thing you can count on. There's one
thing you can count on. If it's 9:00,
9:30, I'm sleep.
>> I'm sleep. I'm done.
>> I'm done.
>> There's no There's no burning the
midnight oil. It ain't old.
>> Hey, what else is going on?
>> I love it. I love it.
up early.
>> You have my respect. Jeez.
>> Okay. So, we are It's rare that we're
here on a Thursday. Uh we've had to push
it back to Thursday this week because of
an event going on if you're inside the
building
>> department amongst employees
>> department trip.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Rough.
>> So, Oh, yeah. So, that means we are
right at two weeks away from the first
day of the NFL draft. We got a lot to
get to.
>> Drum roll.
>> Yeah, man. I'm excited.
>> Excited about it.
>> I am.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> I'm excited. I I think um and I think we
haven't had this conversation about the
draft on whether you guys agree with
best player available, BPA or need.
>> And that's I mean it's obviously two
different philosophies. And the Cowboys
right now, no matter how you boil it
down, I I mean everybody from the
outside really feel like defense is
number one. two, three, four, and five.
Uh, but with the flexibility that they
have at 12 and 20, where do they push
the button knowing right now that they
need a linebacker, right? And and no
moves have been made into that regard
for linebackers didn't do it in free
agency. So, are they loading up and
putting all of their eggs in one basket
and saying, "We're going to find that
guy in this draft in the first round."
Who? If you go best player, let's say
the best player is an offensive player
>> and you he's right there for you.
>> What position?
>> Don't matter. Wide receiver. Wide
receiver. Wide receiver.
>> Well, yeah.
>> No.
>> Running back.
>> Left tackle.
>> Offensive guard.
>> I'd think about it.
>> Oh, we got him right there.
>> Left tackle.
>> I said I'd think about it
>> for guard or tackle.
>> No, he don't think guard.
>> No, he never thinks guard.
>> No guard.
>> Never guard. No, he catch that one. But
you got to tell me who I'm passing on
defense
>> to do that. And is there somebody in the
first round other than the quarterback?
Maybe the running back that would cause
you to change your mind.
>> I like that.
>> Like is there a wide receiver there?
Probably not. Tight end? No. Offensive
lineman? I don't see Tyron Smith in the
top 10. Mhm.
>> So, you would have to tell me what I'm
passing to have somebody like CD Lamb or
Tyron Smith uh or Zack Martin end up in
my lap.
>> Based on what we have on this team right
now, there's no way I would abolish the
plan itself. To me, the plan is to you
need defensive players.
>> That's the plan. I would I would I would
say I don't care who's out there. You
got to you got to stick to the plan.
You're going to have success. Let's say
the running back is there from Ohio
State.
>> You say, "Okay, I'm going to take him."
>> You mean the Notre Dame, right?
>> I'm sorry. Not I was thinking Sunny.
Yeah. Let's say that happens.
>> You He's going to be successful,
>> but that's still not what you need. He's
going to be a successful player. He's
going to have success in this offense,
but you still that's still not what you
want because you're still going to be
giving it up on the other side of the
ball every time,
>> right?
>> Nothing has changed there. Now, even if
you get a second the second pick, third
pick, you still need as more defense.
You still need more defensive players.
And that running back would get in the
way of that if we were to go with Notre
Dame.
>> Let me throw this out at you, Mickey.
Okay. Okay. Hey,
>> what if Okay, there's a certain tier
there of those defensive players who are
potential top 10 picks. There's only a
certain number of those and then it
appears that you would go down to a
second tier there. Let what if all of
those guys are picked before you come on
the board at number 12? And I'll just
run go off of this was I wrote this down
weeks ago. This was D Daniel Jeremiah's
um first listing of his top 50 players
and they included Fernando Mendoza,
Jeremiah Love, top two. Arll Reese,
defensive player, David Bailey,
defensive player. Sunny Styles, Ruben
Bane, he had Ma Lemon next. He's dropped
him since Monsour Delane
and he had Carnell Tate, Caleb DS were
to 10 and then a guard at 11, which
leaves you the next defensive player
he's got on his list is Germad McCoy
coming off the ACL who Mickey says no.
The next defensive player is Colton Hood
or Cashes Hal or Hakee Messador. So,
you've now gone down to the next level
basically, which were he originally had
them um 15th best player and below that.
So, John, you're at 12 and you've picked
over on the guys that you have ranked in
your top 10 with first round grades.
Now, what do you do?
>> Um, if I had a choice of
two or three players,
I'd trade down.
If I found my guy at 12 and the way I've
looked at some mock drafts at 20, I
probably could trade down four or five
spots and still get a defensive guy
because excuse me, some of the mocks
I've seen uh from 20 to
say 27, 25, it's been three or four
offensive linemen, three running backs,
uh I mean uh wide receivers,
uh a tight end and defensive tackles.
So, I could move down at 20 and still
find me either if I need the corner that
I didn't get or a defensive end that I
didn't get at 12.
>> I think it's more likely at 20 than
moving around at
>> I would I would I would not you know we
always are the higher picks are the
higher potential picks. Do we look at
them as a status thing? Because does it
make a difference between the first
player picked and the 20th player picked
or the 30th player picked? These are
still quality individuals. These are
guys that showed off in the draft. They
just, you know, they're just not ranked
as high as some of the offensive players
or the more glamorous players. You look
at that undrafted free agent here. You
know, there's talent, man. Your scouts
got to do their job. We have looked at
so many people do 40s, do shuttles, do
vertical, all of that. We We should know
these guys by the like the back of our
hands if that's your job to do that. And
if you can't find somebody a a 40th
player, a 40th pick from a player, I'm
sorry, you you're not a good scout.
You're not picking a from a from a good
you're not coming from a good place at
all. And I think even with the so-called
draft experts out there, there's a lot
of conflict on whether whether a guy is
the 15th best player in the draft or the
65th best player.
>> Where's the Bible?
>> Which is what is the Bible? You see what
I'm saying? And and so to that point, if
those quote unquote premier players are
gone, okay, then it behooves you to go
ahead and move down some, pick up an
extra second or an early third,
whatever, because that's the meat of the
depth of the draft right there. And
there's, to your point, there's not that
much difference. Or you could could find
the guy that you want, he may still be
available at 55 and uh you're thinking
about picking him at 20. No, you you're
talking about finding a diamond in a
rough and that's what you that's what
you're saying.
>> Well, you you're not playing the
percentage.
>> No, as far as I'm concerned that you're
saying 55th, 40th is a diamond in the
rough.
>> I mean, you're talking about all these
all these college players.
>> I'm going from Everson Wall saying I'm
Look at me. I'm undrafted. I'm saying
no. That's
>> But what I'm saying is a lot of stuff is
missed all the time. That's where I'm
headed. A lot of stuff is missed all the
time. You don't you don't know what
these guys are going to play like when
they get on a team.
>> No.
>> I say 10 of those guys in that top 25 or
30, whatever.
>> Some of them are going to be bumps.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, they're going to be
>> look through the track record throughout
all the drafts in history.
>> We're we're clamoring and clamoring for
I got to get that top. That's why I'm
asking. Is it about status? Right.
Because you want to you want the best of
both worlds. You want the status pick,
but you also want them to perform. Well,
I think when you I mean, you're doing
all this work, right? Doing all this
work.
>> You're ranking your board.
>> I guarantee you a top they'll have 15
guys with first round grades. After
that, those guys are second round grades
that you're going to draft at 20 25,
right? And and look at how the Cowboys
have drafted. If you look at their
history, when they've drafted in the top
17, they they've hit
>> they've hit big,
>> right? And then it falls off when you
get into I don't know where was Mazy 28.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. You just fell off into the second
round. He's not a first round guy,
right?
>> Uh
>> but his body language was was third
round.
>> Well, worse than that.
>> I wouldn't want to use him. Oh, but I'm
just saying when you're getting into the
late 20s, right?
>> What was Gayton 29? That's almost second
round. That is second round basically.
>> Uh you don't hit there as often as you
hit if you look at their history in the
top 17. And I cut it off at 17 uh
because Em Smith
CD was 17, right? Uh Zack Martin was 16.
>> Yeah, that's There's that conventional
wisdom approach that you're talking
about 1 through 17 and 1 through 10
lately. You know, you just think you
can't miss when you're in that top 10.
Cowboys are always seemingly right on
the cusp, right on the outside. And I'm
saying like draft night, somebody's
going to make a mistake. You know it.
Somebody's going to reach on a player
and then a guy is going to fall to you
that again, you may not even thought
that he was c you were capable of
getting this guy. And so when Mickey
says like offensive lineman, I I at
least think about that if one of these
tackles or guys that's in this draft at
12, and I know Cowboy fans don't want to
hear that, but you understand best
player available versus drafting for
need and ever, you as a former player, I
would feel like if you're in that locker
room, you already know what the team
needs. So you don't want to hear
anything.
>> I don't want anything but what we need.
Exactly.
>> I don't want to hear, "Oh, we got the
best player." Well, let's say, you know,
we're back here with with Thurman Steves
back in the day and they say, "We're
gonna pick a defensive back." What?
>> We're leading the league in
interceptions. Why would we pick a
defensive back? We got to go somewhere
else. So, I wouldn't be I wouldn't pick
against the team's needs cuz now you
you're you're just uh piling people on
top of each other. Yeah.
>> And that's not the way you want to go.
And from a historical uh reference, the
last time the Cowboys drafted two first
round picks was Mike Jenkins and Felix
Jones. Correct. Now, I if memory serves,
I don't remember, but before that, was
there a was that draft based off of best
player available or was it need first
when addressing that those two picks?
>> So, it have been 2008.
>> Eight. Yeah.
They I think looked at Felix Jones as a
change up running back, not a guy that
was going to carry the ball 25 times a
game.
>> They like his speed.
>> Yeah. And and
>> Tony Pard of that
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. time.
>> And then and then Jenkins, they needed a
quarterback. Uh and you know what? They
didn't do him any favors because
>> Jenkins
>> because they ended up
uh who was the little cornerback they
brought in with the name and uh his
second or third second year maybe he he
should have been the starter. Um gosh, I
need the book.
>> Uh it was a little short cornerback with
a lot of speed. Everybody knew his name.
>> Yeah. But they he sat behind him
>> and and he had to sit behind him because
they signed him as a free agent.
>> Mike Jenkins was a good quarterback.
They diminished him because of that that
uh that free agent signing. Where's our
book? It's not here.
>> It's not here.
>> I'm I'm looking at that draft and see
the other thing is who did they pass
over in order uh to draft Mike Jenkins.
The guy that I remember I liked was a
wide receiver, Jordy Nelson, who went
number 36 in that draft. Uh, and
>> the reason but they didn't have a need
for a wide receiver because they the
reason they had the two first round
draft picks is they had traded for Roy
Williams.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, actually no, they had given up in
2009. They didn't have one. They and
that's what happened on it. So they
didn't feel like they had a need. They
had to probably on the team then. I'm
got my years right. Okay. So in they
went for position of need right there.
And as it turns out, they got into the
season in 2008
>> and lo and behold, we need a wide
receiver. And so they then traded the
2009 first round draft pick to Detroit
for Roy Williams.
>> And so now the '09 draft, which you can
make the case was the worst draft in the
history of this franchise because they
didn't have a first round pick. the
second round pick they traded out and so
that was a trade down draft but anyway
had you just taken to your point take
the best player available whatever you
take Jordy Nelson in instead of either
Felix Jones or Mike Jenkins in the first
round then you're not making that trade
u so you got to look beyond this one
year you got to look the first round
pick especially you've got him under
control for five years and so yeah you
in my opinion, you draft the best player
available at a position of need, but
across the board, virtually every
position is a position of need if you
look at it from the perspective of the
next four to five years and not just
what's on your depth chart right now.
>> Well, you better have a plan.
>> And then they
>> I mean, you better have a real plan. You
can't just stumble into this.
>> And then the Well, the same thing
happened a decade later where you're
sitting there and Dez Bryant's at the
end of his career and in mid-season you
have to trade for Amari Cooper and give
up a first round draft pick in whatever
year that was. Um, and so
>> that was worth it. well, for Cooper, but
then the next year you're sitting there,
you I don't remember specifically, you
could have taken a wide receiver in the
draft,
>> but you felt like, no, we don't need a
wide receiver because we've got it might
have been, I can't remember who's on the
roster then, 2017,
and instead you're giving up next year's
first round in the middle of the season,
and it was already a lost season by
mid-season when you made that trade to
begin with
>> with with Cooper with Amari Cooper.
Well, it was they 17 they didn't do
anything. So
>> I I I thought when he came in we did
well
to wide receiver.
>> I don't recall winning a Super Bowl in
2017.
>> No, but he turned the season around and
they did the midseason and they made the
playoffs.
>> Yes, that's what I'm talking about. He
turned the season around. Well, 2009
they Bill mentioned it. They had traded
away their first round pick already,
right? And then in the second round they
traded down into the third round and
Wade Phillips had this guy out there
that was going to be this hybrid
linebacker that can play the line of
scrimmage
>> hybrid. and they drafted Jason Williams
out of Western Illinois.
>> That's a blast from I don't even
remember that.
>> Well, well, there's no reason you would.
>> You shouldn't.
>> And he was a bust. And so that was the
first pick in ' 09.
>> How about the next pick?
>> Steven McGee quarterback.
>> No. Robert Brewster.
>> Oh, you mean the ones that I was looking
That's why you called it any of these.
That's what that's how bad that draft
was.
>> Oh my god.
>> And not And the next And then the next
guy was Steven McGee and then Victor
Butler who was not a bad player for a
fourth round pick
>> against you has agents.
>> Um
David Beer. They actually used a fifth
round pick on a kicker.
John Phillips a tight end.
>> Phillips was the best pick in that draft
probably.
>> And he probably was. You're right. But
you when you already used your first,
you traded out of the second to go into
the third and then took Williams. Ah,
that was Yeah, there's a reason why 2010
didn't turn out so well.
>> Well, I I think what was
>> Can I Can I say this first just to make
sure that we got everything right here
that in 2017 the Cowboys did not make
the playoffs. Go ahead.
>> Okay. Well,
so I think what worries me is what you
know with with Christian Parker with
Christian Parker and we've talked about
him that 34 43 whatever it is, you know,
but I've heard him mention positionless
football and having those guys with that
unique ability to be all over the place
and play to their strength. um right now
obviously you can point to one or two or
three maybe guys in your defensive line
that give you that but outside of that
you don't have it right and so he's got
to know that also in his mind state and
and as far as the organization's mind
state is you know I know our offense is
is
>> top five but our defense we gave up the
most points that we've given up in
franchise history and this franchise
been around for a long time so for me
when I ask that question I'm setting it
up because to me best player available
be damned. You know,
>> you brought in a defensive coordinator.
Yes.
>> Because of what happened last year and
then when you go into the draft instead
of getting a defensive player, which is
you got your defensive coordinator,
brand new, ready to make a difference
and then you get a best player available
and he happens to be an offensive
player.
>> Somebody at 12 on defense can help them.
>> Damn right.
>> I'll just go ahead and say that. Damn
right now. somebody at 12 on defense can
help them no matter what the position is
other than, you know, I'm not probably
taking a defensive tackle there, right?
Uh, everybody talks about taking a
safety. And I go, okay, who am I not
taking to take a safety? Am I not taking
a defensive end who might get me 10
sacks?
>> A middle linebacker.
>> A middle linebacker that I sorely need.
So that's why when they say safety, it's
like I I don't know who I'm passing up
to take a
>> He better be very
>> generational generational safety,
>> right? Yeah. Exactly.
>> And I I think
>> So you're Are you talking about Caleb
DS?
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> is he generational?
>> If if Caleb DS is there, I am R. Well, I
wouldn't be there. You're not running.
>> Don't be run.
I would sprint to the
>> So, which means he's not going to be
there,
>> right?
>> I mean, if if we're that smart, 11 other
teams got to be smart.
>> Here's Stranger Things on draft night.
>> Talk about smart. Uh, and he's coached
by Matt Patricia at Ohio State. Matt
Patricia says Caleb DS will be no matter
what NFL team that he walks into their
facility, he will be the smartest player
in the building.
>> Wow. Well, then he that's high praise.
>> He better be able to play in the slot
then.
>> Well, and he can.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> He better be Darren Woodson.
>> And that's exactly when I heard was
listening to someone talk about him and
they were throwing out Brian Branch with
the Lions and some other current players
in the league and what type of player
Derwin James, those type players,
although he's got a different build than
Derwin James. The guy that I was
thinking of, he's he's Darren Woodson is
from a Cowboys perspective. Well, then
can we segue with this then? Do you
trade up to get the sure thing then?
>> No.
>> Oh, come on. Come on.
>> I I think I think what are you going to
trade?
>> You may Hey, you may have to package
your picks and go up and if you can get
up to top five, he get a guaranteed guy.
If you can if you can do it,
>> who would they do that for?
>> Mo Claybourne.
>> Okay.
>> Would you do it to go and get
>> They tra they traded this year. You got
12 and 20. you don't have a second
rounder. In 2012, whatever year that
was, um they had 14 and 45. They traded
those to the Rams to move up to six.
They took Mo Claybourne. Had they stayed
where they were at 14, the Rams took
Michael Brockers, who would have been
really good here for a decade.
>> At 45, they could have taken uh they
could have taken Bobby Wagner at 45.
Speaking of
>> Mhm.
>> Anyway, anyway,
>> come on, guys. You got to cons
>> I need two first round picks.
>> I need players because I don't have a
second and the third ain't till what 95.
So, if I'm going to get move up, I got
to give up two first round picks to get
one.
>> That's a tough one. That's a tough one.
Here's one of the most significant
things I think that
>> heck,
>> we'll see how it plays out, but I think
one of the most significant things that
happened here in the weeks leading up to
the draft was what happened last week in
Knoxville, Tennessee, Germod McCoy
running a 4-3840.
>> The quarterback coming off the ACL 14
months ago. And there's now talk around
the league that Germad McCoy
>> off of surgery
>> will be the first quarterback off the
board after proving quote unquote that
he's healthy 100% running a 4-38
>> u and that a lot of a lot of teams like
him over Delane LSU the significance of
that from a Cowboys perspective if he
goes in the top 10 that's going to push
and and if we're all thinking we don't
know this for sure but If the Cowboys
are saying, "We don't we aren't going to
take a quarterback coming off an ACL."
All right, that pushes down another
player. There's teams uh there's a
couple of offensive linemen, um Maui
Noah from Miami, Fono from Utah who are
potential top 10 picks. Absolutely. that
could as you're as you're watching the
draft unfold, if those two tackles come
off the board in the top 10 picks, if
Carnell Tate, the wide receiver from
Ohio State, comes off the board,
>> you're one of those defensive players
that we talked about earlier in this
segment are going to be there at number
12 for the Cowboys. whether it's um uh
Caleb DS or Delane the quarterback,
Ruben Bane if he falls because of his
short arms, whatever.
>> Um
>> so wait,
>> they were college.
>> My point is the Cowboys I think are
going to be fine staying where they are
at 12 and getting a really good
defensive player at 12.
>> Would you go defensive tackle?
>> No. Defensive tackle in this draft?
>> Yeah. Uh I I believe the best defensive
tackle is Ohio State guy Kaden McDonald
and uh I would he stay away from that.
Yeah, he would be stay away from that
considering what
>> and he's a one technique. He's not a
he's not a get up the field, you know,
three technique, but he was a big reason
those Ohio State guys were doing a lot
of but
>> come on
>> that Mazy Smith was supposed to be that.
>> No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Don't do
that. Don't do him like that.
>> He is really good.
>> Don't put him in the set. See, that's
what that you're cursing the guy when
you do like that.
>> But what I'm saying is
this team has been down that road before
taking a defensive tackle like that in
the first round.
>> I remember saying they said Mazy
>> That's right. He was Micah was more
excited than anybody in the building.
>> He was lifted more weights than anybody.
They gave him some type of title or
something coming out.
>> That was Mazy.
>> Come on, guys. Let's get the brighter
better. Let's go. Let's go to green of
pastures here. All right.
>> They forgot to rate his love for
football.
>> There you go. That's a huge part of
>> the interview must have been deceptive
because they had a chance,
>> you know, when he showed up here the
first day. I I don't He looked like he
loved football. He said all the right
things. They had his mama with him and
it's like, okay,
>> I remember your report
>> and and then and then I don't know what
happened.
>> Well, about the guy. I don't know what
happened. I don't know what happened
with
>> you. Didn't love football.
>> All right, we love breaks here on Mix
Shots. We're going to take a break and
we got much more to get to. Two weeks
away from NFL draft day.
>> We all do it. You keep singing the wrong
lyrics to a song even though you know
they're wrong. You stick with them.
>> So, what you're saying is it's I love
you babe and not lasagna babe. Reminds
me of our people might be sticking with
the wrong insurers, but switching to
Geico can get you the right coverage for
the right price.
>> Oh man, this whole time I thought fire
in my heart was referencing the
heartburn from the lasagna.
>> I hate to break it, Jim.
>> It feels good to get it right. It feels
good to Geico.
>> Hey Cowboy fans, Keith Davis here,
former Cowboy s
>> Keith Davis into the end zone.
>> You know what separates Hamptons from
the rest? Making the right move at the
right moment. With Blockchain.com,
that's never been easier. The Cowboys
became America's team by striking bold
when it matters most. Now it's your
turn. Invest like your icons with
blockchain.com. Visit
blockchain.com/cowboys
today to get started and learn more.
That's blockchain.com/cowboys.
>> Hey Cowboy fans, if you're thinking
about attending a game this season,
visit cowboystravel.com
to book your travel package today. Stay
at the team hotel. Have dinner with a
Cowboys legend and experience the best
sports venue in the world, AT&T Stadium.
Also, tour the Star, get autographs from
your favorite players, and talk X's and
O's with me, Mickey Spagnola, the
official travel partner of the Dallas
Cowboys, will take care of all your
travel needs. Visit cowboystravel.com
to book your package today.
>> The National Medal of Honor Museum is
now open in Arlington, Texas, just a few
blocks from AT&T Stadium. Immersive
exhibits and exciting technology allow
you to fly a rescue helicopter mission
in Vietnam and have conversations with
virtual Medal of Honor recipients. Come
be inspired by these incredible stories
of ordinary Americans who did the
extraordinary. Get your tickets at
mouseum.org or
>> shots.
Here it is, guys. It's time for the
legendary Dallas Cowboys draft party
presented by Miller Lightite. Join us
Thursday, April 23rd at 6 PM inside Ford
Center at the Star in Fris. Watch first
round picks live on the field. Meet
players, see the Dallas Cowboys
cheerleaders perform, and enjoy music,
drinks, and more. Admission is free.
Specs, visit dallascowboys.com/draft.
>> I kind of place.
>> Oh, you got a
>> free. As we welcome you back here, my
voice is getting better. Getting more
normal now.
>> That's a lesson.
>> I was going to say no.
>> That's a lesson that before you do a
talk show, talk before you get on the
air. Okay. Mick Shots presented by
Miller Light, the only beer of the
Cowboys. It's
>> Miller time. I saw something highly
significant this morning from I believe
Tommy Yarish tweeted it out
>> as there are some uh jersey number
changes that are going on behind the
scenes here at the Star.
>> And a significant one
>> as the new safety Jaylen Thompson is
going to be wearing number 34.
What does that mean? That means Savone
Rebel is wearing a different number. I
have not seen what number Rebel is going
to, but are we in agreement that a
quarterback shouldn't be wearing number
34?
>> I agree.
>> Yeah,
>> 24 is a great quarterback number. Yes,
>> that's a great number.
>> That was the first strike against Rebel.
Had nothing to do with his knee.
>> His number.
>> It was his number.
>> It was his number. That's all you
needed, Bill. When I saw him shot out
there with number 34,
>> this is not good. This is not good. He's
doomed.
>> He's wearing 34.
>> Can't give him number 34. I don't care
if he wants it.
>> That's That's too heavy of a number.
That's right. Can't
>> Donovan Esaku is going from 41 to his
college number six.
He is going to have a huge second year
now.
>> So, what happens with number Who had
number six last year?
>> Donovan Wilson.
>> That's right.
>> Okay.
>> You know what? I'm
>> And he's still looking for a job.
>> Yes, he is. And
>> boy, I come off so old school on this,
man. I'm sick of these single-digit
numbers. You don't like
>> I don't 556.
>> I don't like I don't like big small
numbers.
>> Come on. You don't like what?
>> I don't like big guys with small
numbers.
>> Yeah.
the linebackers, lineman, and what like
Oregon, University of Oregon. They
always got big old 300lb guy here
>> with number two.
>> And you know, as an announcer, you're
trying to call that 300lb guys, right?
>> The number I have no idea what this
guy's wearing
>> coming up with.
>> Unbelievable.
>> I don't know. The defensive end for the
Rams is pretty good at number five.
>> Well, that's there's there's always
exceptions and then there's a rule. So,
there you go. You go right to the top,
Mick. Right to the top, Mick. Thank
Thank you, Mick. Right there.
>> That guy you on that one, man.
>> I remember when he showed up at Trading
Cap that his rookie year, they could
>> You're talking Jared Verse.
>> The universe is what we call
>> the universe.
>> They could not They could That is block
him. And he had a mouth that went 100
miles an hour.
>> That's what I'm looking for in this
draft.
>> All right.
>> I want
>> I want a middle linebacker just like
that. And I but I want him I'm always
looking for Michael Irvin. Yes.
>> I want the mouth that's going 100 miles
an hour with
>> And what if confidence?
>> What if he's a top five pick and he's
right there and you've identified that
he is that guy.
>> Find me that guy.
>> I'M NOT GOING TO GIVE UP.
>> SEE MO CLAYBOURNE WASN'T THAT GUY. He
ain't he ain't Clayborn.
>> I don't give up.
>> Heck, right. Mo Claybourne wasn't that
guy, you know. Nicest guy in the world,
you know, to this day. But you need the
nicest guy in the world who is running
his mouth and he's confident and he's
gonna be coming on the field with a with
a boom box on his shoulder certified ass
kicker.
>> That's what you're looking for. You
don't you don't look man like right off
the bus. Nick Eatman said that off the
bus guy. Can Can I get that guy that I
know right away? There's no guesswork in
it. And there's in in this draft, I
think the top eight guys it are like
bonafide defensively that you know you
can't you are not going to miss on that.
And if you can get one of those guys,
>> I take David Bane with them short
anything.
Yeah, give me him because Mick, what do
you say? What did I not see all season
long with Bane? I saw it. I don't he
doesn't have to prove any Ruben Bane has
shown you that man short arms and all he
is a guy day one that you know is going
to make an impact.
I don't think anybody's falling for this
whole conspiracy theory about his arms
being short. Uh some I you know it was
fun to talk about you know we can look
at him from now on I'm going to be
seeing him looking at him you know as
he's prehistoric or something with the
short arms.
But still, I mean,
>> you know what makes up?
>> It's just fun to talk about that guy's
going to he's going to do work. He's
going to do work.
>> He'll make up with for short arms with
an enlarged heart.
>> He's going to do work.
>> This guy will lay it out on the And I
told you guys the story the first time I
saw him play at Miami. And I was like,
are you serious? This guy for real? So I
went to Will Mcclelay and I said, is
Ruben Bane for real? And he looked at me
and he smiled. He'll never get to us.
Just like that. And I said, "Okay, you
answer."
>> And he was aware of his mayor.
>> This was early in the early in the
season watching Miami play.
>> Tell you, I like the other guy at Miami,
too. I messed
>> Messador.
>> And in fact, if you look up uh Meador,
some of his stats could have come
because Ruben Bane was on the other
side, but he actually had 17 and a half
tackles for loss,
>> 14 and a half sacks, something like
that. They terrorize people,
>> right? And he and he's an interesting
story. Messedor is now the the knock on
Messador is he's too old.
>> He's 25 years old and he he's a six-year
guy. Uh now that's a knock now. Now I'll
say that's a knock on him.
>> That's That should be a plus. He's
exceeded.
He's
>> Exactly. He is a walk-in starter. You
don't have to worry about him. He's a
seasoned veteran coming in here. He
actually started his career at West
Virginia and he was playing nose tackle,
coached by at Miami, coached by Jason
Taylor, Hall of Famer. But anyway, he
was his first two years at West
Virginia, he was playing in the
interior, 260, then 270 pounds and was
productive there and then transfers to
Miami. He got a full four years in in at
Miami as well. And his first year there,
I think he had seven sacks. He was
playing on the edge and then because of
need they needed him to move inside and
he played one technique, three technique
as an interior defensive tackle. So his
numbers aren't great there. Yeah, he's
actually hurt in 2023. But in 24 he
aren't the same as what they were in 25.
That's because he was playing a totally
different position. And what Jason
Taylor talked about with him is his
commit his commitment to change his body
from 20 24 to 25. He lost he got down to
260 lbs. He weighed 259 at the combine.
Uh and he lost 4% body fat, whatever.
And and he turned into and he and Jason
Taylor gives him a lot of credit for his
work ethic and so forth. Turned into the
edge rusher that he is now. But he's got
that position flexibility too as an
inside rusher in a nickel scheme as
well. And he is
>> and guess what? He'll play the run.
>> And by the way, and yeah, he and he gets
to the quarterback about the same time
Ruben Bane does.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> Messador put him he's in the mix
>> if if everyone's passed over that top
10. And I would not have a problem with
Messador at number 12, but he's still he
may still be available at 20. and but
he's a guy that I think the Cowboys got
to get a pass rusher with one of those
picks in the first round.
>> Yeah. What what just really makes me
gives me the the ick is the fact that
the Giants are sitting there at five and
the Commanders are sitting there at
seven.
>> Oh man, they they're going to get a
player. They're going to get one of
probably one of these players that we've
been talking about. Either Caleb DS or
Ruben Bane,
>> Sunny Styles,
>> right? Right there at five and seven. So
those are the teams that again are going
to have the pick of the litter on guys
that may drop to them.
>> So that's why you want to trade up.
>> Yes, Bill.
>> Yes.
>> Come on, guys. Let me I'm doing
everything I can ever to win this point.
Um
>> can I trade up without giving up my
other first?
>> Can it happen?
>> I don't know in anywhere.
>> You don't have a second. You don't have
a second.
>> Yeah, I I know. I mean, and I would you
sacrifice that for a sure thing?
>> The I think the only way and I have I
have to look at the trade value chart.
Um, and so I'll have that answer for you
shortly.
>> You would if you're not giving up number
20, let's say to number six, Cleveland.
Okay.
>> You would have to give up your third and
probably a future pick
>> next year. Second or fourth,
>> something like that. Yeah,
>> I would think
>> because that's all they got.
>> Yeah. No,
>> we got we got
>> or a player.
>> We need numbers. We need numbers. We
need more than one defensive.
>> All right, fine. I'm All right. I'm
done. All right. So, I'm just saying.
Fine. We need more than one defensive.
>> I'm surrounded. I'm done. It's okay. All
right. So, has there any have there been
any moves that have not been made in
this off season that concern you?
>> Middle line.
>> Yeah. Middle line.
Well,
and now the this doesn't really concern
me
uh because they're going to take care of
it in the draft, but they pass rusher as
well.
>> Mhm.
>> Is a concern. They haven't filled that
need. I mean, they need a couple
actually. And cornerback is another need
they have because you got to look at it.
They lost Trayvon Dick. even though he
wasn't a Cowboys free agent, you
subtract him from what was on the team
last year, even though he was let go
with a week left in the season. They
have they they got to replace Trayvon
Diggs.
>> Now, they've done thing I like what
they've done in free agency with Kobe
Durant coming in here, Darion Kendrick
as well, which gives puts them in a
position where they don't have to take a
quarterback.
>> They could play tomorrow, right, with
those guys,
>> right? And
>> but
>> and you can take a quarterback in the
third round or whatever, you know, where
if you really like what you have at uh
available at 12 or 20 and you can take a
quarterback and he doesn't have to play
immediately because you get I mean Kobe
Durant played in the NFC Championship
game as did Darion Kendrick last year
for the Rams. So, um, and then and they
they got other guy with Bland coming
back from injury and we'll see where he
is, but others coming back from injury.
>> Do you feel like that's extremely
optimistic to believe that the Cowboys
will find their middle linebacker in the
f for the future in at 12 or 20? Um,
based off of what you know about what
we've done in the draft, are you
>> if if Sunny Styles falls, then they've
got their middle linebacker.
>> Okay. So names like that, it have to be
>> it would have to be Sunny Style. You got
CJ Allen from Georgia who would be in
the mix at 20.
>> You know who I really love is Anthony
Hill Jr.
>> was just going to bring him.
>> Oh man, I love that kid. He's a young
guy. Uh and pair him with Overshon
>> and he could play anywhere.
>> Yeah. Right. And and that's the thing.
Here's what you could do with Anthony
Hill. In fact, I I would consider
Anthony Hill at number 20. As a matter
of fact, I think he's got that kind of
potential. But I but what if they were
to make that move, I think they should
get a veteran guy in free agency to man
the middle, whether it's a OKR or a
Wagner or whatever. Not Wag. Not Yeah,
it right. Yeah, Wagner.
>> I wouldn't.
>> But because Anthony Hill, he can be used
in sub packages. He can be used on the
edge. I mean, he's got he had five sacks
last year for Texas. He's got that kind
I mean, we're talking about Arll Reese
at the top of the draft and he's got
phenomenal physical talent, but he
hasn't played that much. He's a one-year
guy at Ohio State, and he played offball
linebacker, some on the edge, and he's
someone's going to be really happy to
take him at number two or three in the
draft. Anthony Hill's got a lot of the
same skill set uh as with more
experience.
>> Find a little linebacker from the SEC
easily, right?
>> Well, I mean,
>> you just made me feel good because we
had to do this spotlight TV show and
they wanted us to come up with our own
mock draft one through 20. I don't do
mock draft. So, I decided I'm going to
do I'm gonna do it who I want, right?
Not what's going to happen.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I got Bane at 12. And
>> you took Anthony Hill.
>> Anthony Hill at 20.
>> I don't have any problem with that.
>> You guys are the best because literally
no one in ESPN draft prospecting has
Anthony Hill one through 32. So, you
guys have to do your own draft because
no one else sees it the way you do. Uh
it's and it's because you obviously know
what kind of player he is and how he
>> person he is and the whole he fits
exactly the mold of the mold of the
player that Shotimer is looking for.
Tyler Booker who's I mean he's going to
affect other people in the room. He he
has that overshown persona about him. I
mean, a guy very coachable and he's got
tremendous athleticism. When you go back
and look at his time at Denton Ryan and
I mean, he was a he was on the 4x400
meter relay team.
>> Funny story about this kid. Called his
called his game in high school. I'm
standing down on the field and it's a
bright sunny Friday night to a Friday
Friday and uh all of a sudden I feel
shade and there's no clouds in the sky
and it's Anthony Hill standing behind
me. He a man it's a big old dude man.
>> What position does he plays
>> play linebacker? Linebacker edge.
>> Yeah. But
>> so why is he why was he picked why was
he
uh predicted so low in the draft? Well,
most most inside linebackers aren't
projected to go that high. They if you
look at the history, middle linebackers
usually don't get picked. The Lions got
criticized.
>> Unusual for me to to hear that. It
really is. I've always thought
>> The Lions got criticized so much when
they took Jack Campbell with the 18th
pick in the draft in 2023.
>> How'd that work out?
>> Yeah. And they took Jir Gibbs in that
same draft. Now, what are the Lions
doing? They took a running back in the
first round and a middle linebacker in
the first round. What in the world are
they doing? Well, they're going deep in
the playoffs,
>> right?
>> Yeah, they got that guy.
>> You know what happens with those middle
linebackers?
>> Unless they're a hybrid, everybody's
looking at, well, they're a two down
player.
>> They can't play nickel.
>> Yeah,
>> these guys do that,
>> right?
>> And they can blitz, too.
>> Uh the other linebacker, um
>> CJ Allen.
>> Yeah, Allen. Did I see he had somewhat
of a knee thing or did
>> did that delay his senior season?
>> We'll check on that and we'll be back
with more big shots in just a moment.
>> I'm not supposed to be asking questions.
>> Star Sports Tours is the only official
fan travel partner of the Dallas Cowboys
offering exclusive game weekend travel
packages with pregame sideline access
and photo ops with current players,
cheerleaders, and Cowboy legends. You
want to stay at a team hotel? Attend the
best tailgate party in Texas. Tour the
Star and talk X's and O's with me,
Everson Walls. With Star Sports Tours,
you can visit cowboystravel.com
to book your travel package today.
>> The National Medal of Honor Museum is
now open in Arlington, Texas, just a few
blocks from AT&T Stadium. Immersive
exhibits and exciting technology allow
you to fly a rescue helicopter mission
in Vietnam and have conversations with
virtual Medal of Honor recipients. Come
be inspired by these incredible stories
of ordinary Americans who did the
extraordinary. Get your tickets at
mouseum.org.
>> We've all been there. You hold on to a
coupon, hoping to cash it in at the
store, but then you forget about it and
suddenly you've got a mountain of
useless expired coupons.
>> Do you think this one's still good? Free
milk.
>> Oh, mate, that expired in 1993.
>> Dang it.
>> Fortunately, there are better ways to
save money, like by switching to Geico.
You could save about $900 on car
insurance without ever touching a
coupon.
>> Ooh, how about this one? Half off floppy
discs.
>> Now you should try a bit of spring
cleaning.
>> It feels good to save big. It feels good
to Gecko. Hey Cowboy fans, Keith Davis
here, former Cowboy savior.
>> KEITH DAVIS INTO THE END ZONE.
>> You know what separates champions from
the rest? Making the right move at the
right moment. With Blockchain.com,
that's never been easier. The Cowboys
became America's team by striking bold
when it matters most. Now it's your
turn. Invest like your icons with
blockchain.com. Visit
blockchain.com/cowboys
today to get started and learn more.
That's blockchain.com/cowboys
>> back to make shots.
>> Final minute here of Mick Shots brought
to you by Miller Lightite, the only beer
of the Dallas Cowboys. It's Miller time.
CJ Allen, the Georgia linebacker,
suffered a knee injury, a meniscus tear
against Texas on November 15th. He had
the minor procedure to correct it and
was back playing 13 days later.
>> All right, good.
>> So, there's that. All right, final word
comes from whoever wants it.
Nobody wants it.
>> How about you? You got the big green
notebook I saw on TV. Splash.
>> Uh-huh. Did you trade up? Trade up.
>> Trade up. I say
>> don't trade up Cowboys.
>> Trade up Cowboys. Get out of here. Stay
where you are. The best player
available.
>> He's a double agent. This is a double
agent.
>> Trade down at 20.
>> He wants us to lose.
>> Say something about a quarterback.
>> Uh, I don't know. What can you say? Did
we ever figure out who the short guy
was? That's what I wanted.
>> No, I couldn't find his name.
>> They gave you the book.
>> They didn't They didn't sign him as a
free agent. It was the guy that got in
trouble uh at the hotel. Pac-Man.
Pac-Man. Thank you.
>> How do you not remember Pac-Man Jones?
>> Remember it.
>> I mean, I thought of Pac-Man as you were
talking, but I'm sure you're going to
remember Pac-Man.
>> Pac-Man.
>> Wow.
>> They signed Pac-Man and Mike Jenkins got
pushed.
>> Okay. More Pac-Man stories when we get
back together on Monday at 11, right?
>> Yes. here on Mick Shots brought to you
by Miller Lightite. Go Cowboys.
>> This has been a production of
DallasCowboys.com and the Dallas Cowboys
Football Club.
>> How about you, Cowboys?